A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Leadership Development Program (LDP), Accession 2017:027 FA1298
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Southwest Region LDP Fellow files, 1967-1980; 3; 7.84 Cubic Feet About 16.75 LTR size Hollinger boxes and 1 LGL size Hollinger box
  The series consists entirely of Fellow files for the Leadership Development Program Southwest Region Office. For the most part, these files follow the general organizational scheme imposed by the records' creators for all Fellow files documenting the LDP. This means that most Southwest Region Fellows have two files for their associated records: One file holding original narrative reports submitted to Southwest Regional Representative/Program Consultant David Grant by the individual Fellow and one file holding narrative report copies submitted to the Ford Foundation by Grant's office. The Southwest Region files are also comprised of the same type of content as the rest of the Fellow files found within the collection. In addition to narrative reports, they chiefly contain correspondence between Grant and individual Fellows, correspondence between Grant and Ford LDP staff, and correspondence between Grant and organizations that provided internships and other learning opportunities to LDP Fellows. Correspondence generally regards submissions of reports, fellowship progress, fellowship changes, and post-fellowship activities.
  The LDP Southwest Region Selection Committee recruited Fellows from the states of Arizona, California, Colorado, Nevada, New Mexico, Texas, and Utah. Popular Internship placements and collaborating organizations for Southwest LDP Fellows included the American G.I. Forum, the Juarez-Lincoln Center (or Juarez Lincoln University), the Southwest Council of La Raza, the Colorado Migrant Council, the Mexican American Legal Defense and Education Fund, and the Southwest Educational Development Laboratory. Some Fellows' activities also intersected with the work of Federal Government organizations like the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Inter-Agency Committee on Mexican American Affairs. It appears that in addition to quarterly narrative reports, Grant's Office required monthly reports for Fellows of the Southwest Region to submit. This kind of report is found within many Fellow files in the series.
  Many Southwest LDP Fellows focused on developing and improving the economic, education, political, and community organization resources of Mexican American and Native American populations. The Series documents the conflict between Mexican American communities and local school boards throughout various school districts in the late 1960s and early 1970s that often resulted in student protests and boycotts. Fellows assisted and directed different programs and initiatives designed to help these communities improve their children's education opportunities. Many Fellow files hold records related to efforts to address the needs for bilingual education programs and more Mexican American teachers and administrators in public schools with large Mexican American student populations. Fellows also sought to improve education opportunities for adults. Within the series, some files contain materials related to education services for migrant workers.
  Several significant social movements advanced by Mexican Americans during this time period are documented by the press clippings and correspondence collected within the Fellow files as well as by the records concerning the Fellows' program and post-fellowship activities. These movements include the actions of the United Farm Workers union, the Chicano cultural identity movement, and the Mexican American Civil Rights Movement. In regards to the Mexican American Civil Rights Movement, Fellow files include materials that discuss efforts to secure inclusion of Mexican Americans within the Voting Rights Act of 1965 as well as relations between Mexican American civil rights groups and African American civil rights groups. In addition to selecting a large number of Mexican American and Native American-focused Fellows, the LDP Southwest Region also recruited several Fellows that concentrated on helping African American communities. Materials collected in the files of these Fellows document initiatives to establish African American studies programs as well as various programs to nurture individual and community economic development.
  Economic development, bilingual/bicultural education, alcoholism treatment, and public housing are all prevalent subjects within the records of those Fellows who pursued an interest in assisting Native American communities.
  In addition to correspondence and reports, the Series holds newsletters, pamphlets, press clippings, flyers, photographs, and postcards.
  This series was broken into four subseries during processing in order to improve user access to the large number of files produced by the Southwest Region Office.
  Series 3 Subseries 1. A-F, 1967-1977
  Series 3 Subseries 2. G-M, 1967-1977
  Series 3 Subseries 3. N-S, 1967-1980
  Series 3 Subseries 4. T-Z, 1967-1977
  - A-F, 1967-1977; 1; 2.2 Cubic Feet 5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    Subseries contains Fellow files for Southwest Region Leadership Development Program Fellows whose last names begin with the letters A-F.
    - Abeyta, John D. - Dulce, New Mexico, 1970-1972 (Box 27, Folder 350)
    - Abeyta, John D. - Dulce, New Mexico, 1970-1972 (Box 27, Folder 351)
      1. Regular Reports
      2. General Correspondence
    - Acosta, Abel G. - Lubbock, Texas, 1968-1970 (Box 27, Folder 352)
    - Acosta, Abel G. - Lubbock, Texas, 1968-1975 (Box 27, Folder 353)
    - Aguinaga, Herminia P. - Eagle Pass, Texas, 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 354)
      Leadership Development Program Fellows Herminia P. and Rene M. Aguinaga were a married couple who traveled to the same locations during their shared fellowship year. However, they developed individual programs and generally engaged in different activities at these locations. Thus, they submitted different reports to Southwest LDP Regional Representative/Program Consultant David Grant, and users will find these reports within the Fellows' respective files.
    - Aguinaga, Herminia P. - Eagle Pass, Texas, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 355)
    - Aguinaga, Rene M. - Eagle Pass, Texas, 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 356)
    - Aguinaga, Rene M. - Eagle Pass, Texas, 1968-1971 (Box 27, Folder 357)
    - Alcocer, Francisco R. - Goodyear, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 358)
    - Alcocer, Francisco R. - Goodyear, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 359)
    - Andazola, Henry H. - Eloy, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 360)
    - Andazola, Henry H. - Eloy, Arizona, 1971-1975 (Box 27, Folder 361)
    - Aragon, Manuel L. - Alamosa, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 362)
    - Aragon, Manuel L. - Alamosa, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 363)
    - Archuleta, Dave S. - Durango, Colorado, 1974-1975 (Box 27, Folder 364)
    - Armendariz, Abe L. - Hurley, New Mexico, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 365)
      Leadership Development Program Fellows Abe L. and Emma J. Armendariz were a married couple who were granted a joint fellowship. They engaged in both shared and separate activities, and they submitted different reports to Southwest LDP Regional Representative/Program Consultant David Grant. Users will find these reports within the Fellows' respective files.
    - Armendariz, Abe L. - Hurley, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 366)
    - Armendariz, Emma J. - Hurley, New Mexico, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 367)
    - Armendariz, Emma J. - Hurley, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 368)
    - Armendariz, Graciela - San Miguel, New Mexico, 1974-1976 (Box 28, Folder 369)
    - Arredondo, Santiago G. - Lordsburg, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 370)
    - Arredondo, Santiago G. - Lordsburg, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 371)
    - Arrellano, Tom L. - Blanca, Colorado, 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 372)
    - Arquero, Joseph S. - Cochiti, New Mexico, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 373)
    - Arquero, Joseph S. - Cochiti, New Mexico, 1969-1970; File includes a set of twelve still images titled Fire Prevention. (Box 28, Folder 374)
    - Atencio, Charles G. - Cebolla, New Mexico, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 375)
    - Atencio, Charles G. - Cebolla, New Mexico, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 376)
    - Atencio, Jose R. - Cuba, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 377)
    - Atencio, Jose R. - Cuba, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 378)
    - Beck, Ima Jean - Corsicana, Texas, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 379)
    - Beck, Ima Jean - Corsicana, Texas, circa 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 380)
    - Becknell, Charles E. - Corrales, New Mexico, 1967-1973 (Box 28, Folder 381-382)
    - Becknell, Charles E. - Corrales, New Mexico, 1968-1971 (Box 28, Folder 383)
    - Begay, Tommy K. - Many Farms, Arizona, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 384)
    - Begay, Tommy K. - Many Farms, Arizona, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 385)
    - Beltran, Frances G. - Central, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 386)
    - Beltran, Frances G. - Central, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 387)
    - Benavides, Felipe - Encino, Texas, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 388)
    - Benavides, Felipe - Encino, Texas, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 389)
    - Bowler, G. Lynn - Overton, Nevada, 1967-1971 (Box 29, Folder 390)
    - Bowler, G. Lynn - Overton, Nevada, 1967-1969 (Box 29, Folder 391)
    - Brown, Orlando - Espanola, New Mexico, 1969-1972 (Box 29, Folder 392)
    - Brown, Orlando - Espanola, New Mexico, 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 393)
    - Bunnell, Max E. - Overton, Nevada, 1967-1969 (Box 29, Folder 394)
    - Bunnell, Max E. - Overton, Nevada, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 395)
    - Calabaza, Delfino - Santo Domingo, New Mexico, 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 396)
    - Cardenas, Jess - Coolidge, Arizona, 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 397)
    - Chavez, Alcario - Sandia Pueblo, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 29, Folder 398)
    - Chavez, Alcario - Sandia Pueblo, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 29, Folder 399)
    - Chavez, Arnold - Alamosa, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 400)
    - Chavez, Arnold - Alamosa, Colorado, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 401)
    - Chavez, Moises A. - San Luis, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 402)
    - Chavez, Moises A. - San Luis, Colorado, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 403)
    - Chavez, Rebecca P. - Sonora, Texas, 1971-1975 (Box 29, Folder 404)
    - Coca, Robert - Cuba, New Mexico, 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 405)
    - Cordova, Gilbert Benito - Gallina, New Mexico, 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 406)
    - Cordova, Gilbert Benito - Gallina, New Mexico, 1970-1976 (Box 30, Folder 407)
    - Cordova, Lucille - Alamosa, Colorado, 1972-1976 (Box 30, Folder 408)
      There is also a segment of records documenting communications between Leadership Development Program Southwest Regional Representative/Program Consultant David H. Grant and the Southwest Council of La Raza concerning LDP Fellow Lucille Cordova, other LDP fellows, and the relationship between the LDP and the Council. The records also document communications between Grant and Cordova that concern her placement with the Council.
      Original folder subheadings within this group of records include:
      1. Correspondence
      2. Activity Record
      3. Forms
      4. LDP Fellows
    - Cordova, Lucille - Alamosa, Colorado, 1972-1973 (Box 30, Folder 409)
    - Craig, Carson - Crownpoint, New Mexico, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 410)
    - Craig, Carson - Crownpoint, New Mexico, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 411)
    - Crawford, Paul I. - Cortez, Colorado, 1967-1969 (Box 30, Folder 412)
    - Crawford, Paul I. - Cortez, Colorado, 1967-1969 (Box 30, Folder 413)
    - Criddle, Willie, Jr. - Corsicana, Texas, 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 414)
    - Criddle, Willie, Jr. - Corsicana, Texas, 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 415)
    - Defender, Adelina T. - Ignacio, Colorado, 1968-1970 (Box 30, Folder 416)
    - Defender, Adelina T. - Ignacio, Colorado, 1968-1970 (Box 30, Folder 417-418)
    - De Halle, Normando R. - Avondale, Arizona, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 419)
    - De Halle, Normando R. - Avondale, Arizona, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 420)
    - Delgado, Rita - Mesilla, New Mexico, 1974-1977 (Box 31, Folder 421)
    - Duran, Gilberto R. - Espanola, New Mexico, 1968-1969 (Box 31, Folder 422)
    - Duran, Gilberto R. - Espanola, New Mexico, 1968-1972 (Box 31, Folder 423)
    - Duran, Robert J. - Garfield, New Mexico, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 424)
    - Estrada, Beatrice T. - Gallup, New Mexico, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 425)
    - Estrada, Beatrice T. - Gallup, New Mexico, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 426)
    - Estrada, Ramon E. - Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1967-1970 (Box 31, Folder 427)
    - Estrada, Ramon E. - Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1967-1976 (Box 31, Folder 428)
    - Esquerra, Ronald L. - Phoenix, Arizona, 1970-1972 (Box 31, Folder 429)
    - Esquerra, Ronald L. - Phoenix, Arizona, 1969-1976 (Box 31, Folder 430)
    - Esquibel, Ezekiel, Jr. - Belen, New Mexico, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 431)
    - Esquibel, Ezekiel, Jr. – Belen, New Mexico, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 432)
    - Fortson, Bobby Elliott - Kilgore, Texas, 1970-1972 (Box 31, Folder 433)
    - Fortson, Bobby Elliott - Kilgore, Texas, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 434)
    - Frazier, Robert D. - Harquahala, Arizona, 1968-1970 (Box 31, Folder 435)
    - Frazier, Robert D. - Harquahala, Arizona, 1968-1970 (Box 31, Folder 436)
  - G-M, 1967-1977; 2; 2.6 Cubic Feet 5 LTR size Hollinger boxes and 1 LGL size Hollinger box
    Subseries contains Fellow files for Southwest Region Leadership Development Program Fellows whose last names begin with the letters G-M.
    - Gallegos, Sister Jacinta - Antonito, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 437)
    - Gallegos, Sister Jacinta - Antonito, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 438)
    - Gallegos, Robert G. - Antonito, Colorado, 1970-1972 (Box 32, Folder 439)
    - Gallegos, Robert G. - Antonito, Colorado, 1970-1972 (Box 32, Folder 440)
    - Galvan, Adelfa A. - Thorndale, Texas, 1973-1974 (Box 32, Folder 441)
    - Galvan, Adelfa A. - Thorndale, Texas, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 442)
    - Garcia, Angelita - Mercedes, Texas, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 443)
    - Garcia, Angelita - Mercedes, Texas, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 444)
    - Garcia, Ernesto R. - Avondale, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 445)
    - Garcia, Ernesto R. - Avondale, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 446)
    - Garcia, Raul J., Jr. - Falfurrias, Texas, 1974-1976 (Box 32, Folder 447)
    - Garza, Leocadio, Jr. - Edinburg, Texas, 1970-1972 (Box 32, Folder 448)
    - Garza, Leocadio, Jr. - Edinburg, Texas, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 449)
    - Garza, Porfirio - Asherton, Texas, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 450)
    - Garza, Porfirio - Asherton, Texas, 1970-1977 (Box 32, Folder 451)
    - Gomez, David - Taos Pueblo, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 452)
    - Gomez, David - Taos Pueblo, New Mexico, 1972-1977 (Box 32, Folder 453)
    - Gonzales, Lorenzo - Cuba, New Mexico, 1974-1976 (Box 32, Folder 454)
    - Guerra, Eloy P. - Concepcion, Texas, 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 455)
    - Guerra, Eloy P. - Concepcion, Texas, 1969-1970; File includes a still image of LDP Fellow Eloy Guerra with his son. (Box 33, Folder 456)
    - Gutierrez, Cilfredo R. - Monte Vista, Colorado, 1972-1973 (Box 33, Folder 457)
    - Gutierrez, Cilfredo R. - Monte Vista, Colorado, 1972-1973 (Box 33, Folder 458)
    - Gutierrez, Robert S. - Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1974-1975 (Box 33, Folder 459)
    - Harris, Abraham, Jr. - Arizona, circa 1973-1974 (Box 33, Folder 460)
    - Hart, Norris G. - Corsicana, Texas, 1968-1970 (Box 33, Folder 461-462)
    - Hart, Norris G. - Corsicana, Texas, 1968-1969; File includes three still images of LDP Fellow Norris Hart. (Box 33, Folder 463)
      2. Original Application
    - Heflin, John F. - Merced, California, 1970-1972 (Box 33, Folder 464)
    - Heflin, John F. - Merced, California, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 465)
    - Hernandez, Santos H. - Lytle, Texas, 1974-1975 (Box 33, Folder 466)
    - Hernandez, Rene O. - Carrizo Springs, Texas, 1974-1976 (Box 33, Folder 467)
    - Jimenez, Ruben Sotelo - Buckeye, Arizona, 1970-1972 (Box 33, Folder 468)
    - Jimenez, Ruben Sotelo - Buckeye, Arizona, 1969-1971 (Box 33, Folder 469)
    - Jiron, Marie K. - Isleta Pueblo, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 33, Folder 470)
    - Jiron, Marie K. - Isleta Pueblo, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 33, Folder 471)
    - Johnson, Ronald E. - Dateland, Arizona, 1967-1969 (Box 33, Folder 472)
    - Johnson, Ronald E. - Dateland, Arizona, 1967-1968 (Box 33, Folder 473)
    - Johnston, Dorothy W. - Monahans, Texas, 1967-1971 (Box 34, Folder 474)
    - Johnston, Dorothy W. - Monahans, Texas, 1967-1972 (Box 34, Folder 475)
    - La Plante, Esther L. - Tumacacori, Arizona, 1969-1972 (Box 34, Folder 476)
    - La Plante, Esther L. - Tumacacori, Arizona, 1969-1973 (Box 34, Folder 477)
    - Ledoux, Eugene P. - Pojoaque, New Mexico, 1968-1971 (Box 34, Folder 478)
    - Ledoux, Eugene P. - Pojoaque, New Mexico, 1968-1972 (Box 34, Folder 479-480)
    - Little, Edward M. - Mescalero, New Mexico, 1969-1970 (Box 34, Folder 481)
    - Little, Edward M. - Mescalero, New Mexico, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 482)
    - Lopez, Samuel - Texas, circa 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 483)
    - Lovato, Jimmy D. - San Luis, Colorado, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 484)
    - Lovato, Jimmy D. - San Luis, Colorado, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 485)
    - Lozano, William R. - Walsenburg, Colorado, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 486)
    - Lozano, William R. - Walsenburg, Colorado, 1971-1974 (Box 34, Folder 487)
    - Lucero, Aniceto - Antonito, Colorado, 1968-1970 (Box 35, Folder 488)
    - Lucero, Aniceto - Antonito, Colorado, 1968-1970 (Box 35, Folder 489)
    - Lucero, Manuel T. - Central, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 490)
    - Lucero, Manuel T. - Central, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 491)
    - Luera, Lidia S. - Kearney, Arizona, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 492)
    - Luera, Lidia S. - Kearney, Arizona, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 493)
    - Maestas, Leo C. - Bernalillo, New Mexico, 1967-1970 (Box 35, Folder 494)
    - Maestas, Leo C. - Bernalillo, New Mexico, 1967-1973 (Box 35, Folder 495)
    - Maestas, Ronald W. - Romeo, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 496)
    - Maestas, Ronald W. - Romeo, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 497)
    - Martinez, C. Arthur - Belen, New Mexico, 1969-1971 (Box 35, Folder 498)
    - Martinez, C. Arthur - Belen, New Mexico, 1969-1971 (Box 35, Folder 499)
    - Martinez, Arthur S. - Espanola, New Mexico, 1967-1970 (Box 35, Folder 500)
      File contains a photocopy of a newspaper clipping that concerned Leadership Development Program Fellow C. Arthur Martinez. The photocopy was likely placed within Arthur S. Martinez' file by mistake.
      The original clipping can be found in C. Arthur Martinez's second Fellow file (Folder 499).
    - Martinez, Arthur S. - Espanola, New Mexico, 1968-1972 (Box 35, Folder 501)
    - Martinez, Feliberto - Los Lunas, New Mexico, 1969-1973 (Box 36, Folder 502)
    - Martinez, Feliberto - Los Lunas, New Mexico, 1969-1973 (Box 36, Folder 503-504)
    - Martinez, Homero A. - New Mexico, circa 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 505)
    - Martinez, Ike - San Ildefonso, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 506)
    - Martinez, Ike - San Ildefonso, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 507)
    - Martinez, Jesus D. - Mancos, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 508)
    - Martinez, Jesus D. - Mancos, Colorado, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 509)
    - Martinez, Mauro D. - New Mexico, circa 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 510)
    - Martinez, Rebecca A. - Alameda, New Mexico, 1972-1974 (Box 36, Folder 511)
    - Martinez, Rebecca A. - Alameda, New Mexico, 1972-1974 (Box 36, Folder 512)
    - Martinez, Roberta I. - Alamosa, Colorado, 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 513)
    - Martinez, Roberta I. - Alamosa, Colorado, 1973-1975 (Box 36, Folder 514)
    - Martinez, M. Viola - Espanola, New Mexico, 1969-1971 (Box 36, Folder 515)
    - Martinez, M. Viola - Espanola, New Mexico, 1969-1971 (Box 36, Folder 516)
    - Medrano, Reyes E. - Tolleson, Arizona, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 517)
    - Medrano, Reyes E. - Tolleson, Arizona, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 518)
    - Merchant, Hercel W. - Sells, Arizona, 1967-1970 (Box 36, Folder 519)
    - Merchant, Hercel W. - Sells, Arizona, 1968-1970 (Box 36, Folder 520)
    - Meza, Socorro - Cashion, Arizona, 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 521)
    - Meza, Socorro - Cashion, Arizona, 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 522)
    - Miller, Pat Chee - Fort Defiance, Arizona, 1969-1977 (Box 37, Folder 523)
    - Miller, Pat Chee - Fort Defiance, Arizona, 1969-1974 (Box 37, Folder 524-525)
    - Montalvo, Leo - Mission, Texas, 1969-1971 (Box 37, Folder 526)
    - Montalvo, Leo - Mission, Texas, 1969-1972; File includes two still images. One is untitled, and the other depicts the Alice Demonstration. (Box 37, Folder 527-528)
    - Montoya, Juan E. - Espanola, New Mexico, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 529)
    - Montoya, Juan E. - Espanola, New Mexico, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 530)
    - Mora, Agueda - La Mesa, New Mexico, 1974-1975 (Box 37, Folder 531)
    - Morales, John O. - Yuma, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 37, Folder 532)
    - Morales, John O. - Yuma, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 37, Folder 533)
    - Morelan, Katherine M. - Pecos, Texas, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 534)
    - Morelan, Katherine M. - Pecos, Texas, 1970-1971 (Box 37, Folder 535)
  - N-S, 1967-1980; 3; 2 Cubic Feet About 4.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    Subseries contains Fellow files for Southwest Region Leadership Development Program Fellows whose last names begin with the letters N-S.
    - Naranjo, Carlos A. - Mira Loma, California, 1969-1971 (Box 38, Folder 536)
    - Naranjo, Carlos A. - Mira Loma, California, 1969-1973 (Box 38, Folder 537)
    - Nelson, Kerry D. - Tropic, Utah, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 538)
    - Nelson, Kerry D. - Tropic, Utah, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 539)
    - Nelson, Tommy, Jr. - Wichita Falls, Texas, 1968-1971 (Box 38, Folder 540)
      This is one of the Fellow files that was reintegrated into the Southwest Region LDP Fellow files Series during processing. See Series Scope and Contents note for more information.
    - Nelson, Tommy, Jr. - Wichita Falls, Texas, 1968-1972 (Box 38, Folder 541)
    - Ochoa, Abel P. - Alamo, Texas, 1970-1972 (Box 38, Folder 542)
    - Ochoa, Abel P. - Alamo, Texas, 1969-1973 (Box 38, Folder 543)
    - Ojeda, David, Jr. - Carrizo Springs, Texas, 1971-1972 (Box 38, Folder 544)
    - Ojeda, David, Jr. - Carrizo Springs, Texas, 1971-1972 (Box 38, Folder 545)
    - Ortega, A. Paul - Mescalero, New Mexico, 1969-1977 (Box 38, Folder 546)
    - Ortega, A. Paul - Mescalero, New Mexico, 1969-1972 (Box 38, Folder 547)
    - Ortega, Pete - Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1970-1972 (Box 39, Folder 548)
    - Ortega, Pete - Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1970-1971 (Box 39, Folder 549)
    - Ortiz, Abel R. - Cotulla, Texas, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 550)
    - Ortiz, Abel R. - Cotulla, Texas, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 551)
    - Ortiz, Alfonso, Jr. - Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1968-1971 (Box 39, Folder 552)
    - Ortiz, Alfonso, Jr. - Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1968-1973; File includes two still images attached to LDP Fellow Alfonso Ortiz Jr.'s research report "Research Project on: Twenty-three Supervisory Teachers from the Normal School 'Carlos Zambrano' and Is Laboratory Schools in the Pichincha Province, Quito Ecuador". (Box 39, Folder 553)
    - Ortiz, Ben G. - Silver City, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 554)
    - Ortiz, Ben G. - Silver City, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 555)
    - Pacheco, Patricia A. - Laguna, New Mexico, 1972-1974 (Box 39, Folder 556)
    - Pacheco, Patricia A. - Laguna, New Mexico, 1972-1974 (Box 39, Folder 557)
    - Palmer, Carleton - Mescalero, New Mexico, 1974-1975 (Box 39, Folder 558)
    - Paytiamo, Stanley - Acoma, New Mexico, 1968-1970 (Box 39, Folder 559)